If HMM's work why do we need a new model.
既然 HMM 可以用 为什么我们还需要新模型呢？
It comes down to potential.
这就与潜力有关了
Suppose we have all the data we need and all the processing power we want.
假设我们不缺数据 也不缺处理能力
How far can an HMM model take us,
HMM 模型可以走多远呢？
and how far could some other model take us?
其它模型又能走多远呢？
According to by Baidu's Adam Coates in a recent presentation,
据百度 Adam Coates 在最近的展示里称
additional training of a traditional ASR levels off inaccuracy.
就算对传统 ASR 额外施加训练 准确率也提高不了
Meanwhile, Deep Neural Network Solutions are unimpressive with
而深度神经网络虽然在处理小数据集时平平无奇
small data sets but they shine as we increase data and model sizes.
可一旦数据增加 模型加大 这种网络就能大放异彩
Here's the process we've looked at so far.
这是我们到目前为止说到的过程
We extract features from the audio speech signal with MFCC.
用 MFCC 从音频语音信号里提取特征
Use an HMM acoustic model to convert to sound units, phonemes, or words.
用 HMM 声学模型把特征转化成声音单位、音素或单词
Then, it uses statistical language models such as N-grams to
然后用数据语言模型 如 N 元模型
straighten out language ambiguities and create the final text sequence.
来解决语义模糊问题 生成最终的文本序列
It's possible to replace the many tune parts with a multiple layer deep neural network.
如果用多层深度神经网络 这其中的许多调整部分都可以替换掉
Let's get a little intuition as to why they can be replaced.
我们来看为什么这些部分可以替换
In feature extraction, we've used models based on
特征提取时 我们用的模型
human sound production and perception to convert a spectrogram into features.
会根据人体发声机制和声音感知机制来将频谱图转为特征
This is similar, intuitively,
这听起来与用卷积神经网络
to the idea of using Convolutional Neural Networks to extract features from image data.
从图像数据里提取特征的思路很类似
Spectrograms are visual representations of speech.
频谱图就是语音的视觉表示
So, we ought to be able to let a CNN
所以我们应该能让 CNN
find the relevant features for speech in the same way.
用同样的办法找出相应的语音特征
An acoustic model implemented with HMMs,
与 HMM 一起实现的声学模型
includes transition probabilities to organize time series data.
是用转换概率来组织时序数据的
Recurrent Neural Networks can also track time series data through memory,
而借助记忆 循环神经网络也能跟踪时序数据
as we've seen in earlier lessons on RNNs.
这点在之前的 RNN 课程里讲过
The traditional model also uses HMMs to sequence sound units into words.
传统模型还用 HMM 来排序声音单元 使之成为单词
The RNNs produce probability densities over each time slice.
但 RNN 则是生成各时间切片的概率密度
So we need another way to solve the sequencing issue.
所以我们需要另找办法来解决排序问题
A Connectionist Temporal Classification layer
联结主义时序分类层
is used to convert the RNN outputs into words.
就用于将 RNN 输出转换成单词
So, we can replace the acoustic portion of
所以我们可以把网络的声学部分
the network with a combination of RNN and CTC layers.
替换成 RNN 与 CTC 层的组合
The end-to-end DNN still makes linguistic errors,
端对端深度神经网络仍会有语言学错误
especially on words that it hasn't seen in enough examples.
特别是对样本不够充分的单词
It should be possible for the system to learn language probabilities
系统可以从音频数据中学习语言概率
from audio data but presently there just isn't enough.
但目前来说样本仍不够
The existing technology of N-grams can still be used.
所以我们仍可以用现有的 N 元技术
Alternately, a Neural Language Model can be trained on massive amounts of available text.
另外 可以用数量庞大的文本来训练神经语言模型 (NLM)
Using an NLM layer,
使用 NLM 层
the probabilities of spelling and context can be re scored for the system.
我们就可以重新为系统算出拼写和语境概率了